Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Notice Period: 1 Month

Information Technology]

Suresh Pasupuleti () Featured

Senior Consultant seeking roles in Application Development, Client Servicing, Continuous Integration, Product Design and Development, Integration Testing, Agile, Core Java, Micro Services, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Azure, AWS, Angular Js, Javascript



Current Designation: Senior Application Developer

Current Company: Mashreq Bank (Optimum Info Sytems)

Current Location: Dubai

Pref. Location: Dubai, United Arab Emirates (UAE), United

Kingdom (UK)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Software Developer, Application Development, Client Servicing, Continuous Integration, Design Development, Product Development, Requirement Analysis, Integration Testing, Agile, Core Java, JSP Servlets,

Maven, Spring, AWS, Azure

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

10+ years of IT experience in Development and Client Server application using Java, J2EE Technologies.

Solid Experience in Objected oriented development, Design patterns and multithreading.

Hands on experience in developing web Application using state of art technologies like Core Java, Servlets, JSP, Struts (1.2 & 2), Hibernate, Liquibase, Spring (Core, MVC, Batch, JDBC, Restful, Security, JPA & Spring Boot), Kafka, JMS, Dockers, SOAP, Rest web services and Swagger UI.

Experience in SAP HANA, mongoDB, CouchDB, SQL Server, Oracle 10g /11g RAC, MySQL and PL/SQL.

Experience in the client-side technologies using JavaScript, AngularJS, Angular 6, NodeJS, ReactJS and jQuery.

Hands on experience in designing web pages (HTML and CSS).

Experience in Java 8 Concepts like Lambda Expressions, Streams API and Collection API.

Performance Tuning (JMeter & JProfiler tools)

Experience in Health Checks and Integration Tests.

Experience in cloud servers like aws, azure and google

Work Experience

Mashreq Bank (Optimum Info Sytems) as Senior Application Developer

May 2020 to Till Date

working as Senior application developer and involved the design and development of new user interface components and back-end processing capabilities for an exciting system enhancement.

Participated in complete software development lifecycle, including performance, design, development, and testing.

Responsible for API Connect and validations of gateway endpoints

Worked on Azure cloud and responsible for complete pipeline lifecycle.

Performed fully automated unit testing using Junit

Worked on rest, soap API's and worked with micro services architecture.

Used JVM, java8, Spring Boot, Junit, Mockito and CICD architecture.

Wipro as Associate Consultant Feb 2020 to May 2020 Led a team in the design and development of new user interface components and back-end processing capabilities for an exciting system enhancement.

Participated in complete software development lifecycle, including performance, design,

development, and testing.

Responsible for API Connect and validations of gateway endpoints

Worked on Azure cloud and responsible for complete pipeline lifecycle.

Capgemini as Senior Consultant

Jul 2018 to Feb 2020

Led a team in the design and development of new user interface components and back-end processing capabilities for an exciting system enhancement.

Participated in complete software development lifecycle, including performance, design, development, and testing.

Performed Health checks and Integration tests using rest-based architecture (Rest-assured and Arquillian).

Developed fully automated processes using Jenkins and test scripts (Junit, Mockito and Integration Tests).

Developed RESTful webservices and implemented Liquibase extension for SAP HANA.

Engaged with system engineering team to define functional capabilities based on new requirements.

Mentored junior developers in usage of design patterns, best practices, program coding standards and procedures.

Participated in the development of business strategy (using Spring Boot, Spring-security, JPA and Spring MVC).

Performed o-auth authorization and implemented used based services for authentications.

Syniverse Technologies India Pvt Itd as Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2016 to Jul 2018

Implemented new features(block/unblock) using Spring boot and Rest webservices.

Participated actively in the complete software development lifecycle, including performance analysis, design, development, and testing

Performed fully automated unit testing using Junit, Mockito and TestNG

Created Angular Controllers with rest API calls and Spring MVC controllers.

Involved in developing browser compatibility using React Js, angular JS and Angular4.

Engaged with system engineering team to define functional capabilities based on new requirements.

Implemented Micro Services architecture with Spring Boot and created multilayered environment

Implemented distributed service layers for different DB (mongo DB, Couch DB and Oracle) calls.

Collabera Technologies as Software Engineer

Jul 2014 to Feb 2016

Collaborated with team to understanding new requirements and enhancements.

Participated in the complete software development lifecycle, including design, development, and testing Performed fully automated unit testing using Junit.

Consumed SOAP Webservices and generated client code using axix2 to trigger the notifications using Spring Batch.

Involved in developing role-based security for the application using spring-security.

Engaged with architectural team to define functional capabilities based on new requirements. Automated table loads by allowing authorized users to update tables through web application.

Created web-enabled solutions for consumers that monitor critical changes (CRUD operations).

Worked on L2 support in Application Maintenance phase.

Supported for UAT and Sandbox testing.

Alt Wing Technologies as Software Engineer

Jan 2012 to Jul 2014

Analyzing client's requirements and Involved in developing the coding and designing.

Responsible for following up the client with queries while analyzing the requirements.

Involved in developing the code for action classes and action forms using struts/spring framework.

Facilitate to Update all the fields and products, price details in the admin view

Design and development of applications using Java, J2EE, Springs, Struts2, Hibernate & XML.

Involved in Customer Registration, Preparing Invoice modules

Handle total login validations and generated login authentications at every view of the project.

Automates table loads by allowing authorized users to update tables through web application.

Ability for users to update Test databases live.

The Placard Software Solutions as Technical Consultant

Jun 2010 to Jan 2012

Designed and developed high-volume, low-latency applications and delivering high-availability and performance

Contributing in all phases of the development lifecycle

Writing well designed, testable, efficient code.

Prepared and produced releases of software components

Supported continuous improvement by investigating alternatives and technologies and presenting these for architectural review.

Involved peer code reviews to understand/follow the coding standards.

Responsible to follow up the client tickets/queries for the product requirements/enhancements.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Information Technology) from jawaharlal nehru technology university in 2010

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

ITIL 4 foundation

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
CORE JAVA	8	2021	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
spring boot	2.0	2021	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MySQL	6.0	2019	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Angular js	1.X	2018	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL Server	18.5	2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SPRING MVC	4.X	2021	8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
CORE JAVA	6.0	2021	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Struts	2.X	2018	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MAVEN	4	2021	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Hibernate	5	2018	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Telugu	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: Dubai

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time